Hello everyone. Welcome to the session
about what's new in Expense Agent, the
mobile app.
I'm going to talk to you quickly about
how you can use our new Expense Agent
mobile app. You can scan one or multiple
receipts directly from the app, or you
can also upload receipts that you have
already in your um
gallery. You can also use the mileage
feature just the same way as you can
with a normal Expense Agent web app
view.
Um and I am also going to talk quickly
about what offline mode is and how you
can uh submit your expenses and use
every uh Expense Agent feature directly
from the mobile app.
So, I have now switched to my uh Expense
Agent mobile app, and as you can see, I
can see my feed here with the previously
uploaded expenses that I still haven't
submitted.
But, in my case, what I want to show you
is if I click the plus button, I get
options to scan receipts, choose from
files, or add mileage.
I will you choose scan receipts. And you
can see that we're using here a native
capability, which is called auto capture
from the operating system.
And that means that I can basically just
bring a receipt into the screen, and it
will be automatically captured. And if I
click the plus button on the right,
I can actually upload several receipts
at the same time.
I can of course just have one, but let's
say that um I just have a bunch of
receipts from my trip that I want to
upload at the same time. I can just have
them very quickly recognized by the
system, um and then the moment I click
next, they're just going to be uploaded,
and um
the Expense Agent is going to process
them, and is going to recognize them um
just the same way that you know already
from the Business Central web app.
If now I switch, and I go to the
gallery, I have also some receipts that
I took already a picture of before.
And what I want to show you is that
let's say that you have a bunch of such
pictures that you want to upload
to the Expensify agent, you can use the
share functionality.
So, if you go to the list of apps that
are supported in your um operating
system, you can see that Expensify agent
is now going to pop up here in the list.
And you can just choose Expensify agent,
and your receipt will be then processed
by the Expensify agent as well.
Um so, these are different ways you can
upload
your receipts um to the Expensify agent
using the mobile app.
The additional thing that I want to show
you is also mileage experience.
So, here you can create a mileage
expense directly from your phone.
So, here, for example, let's say I want
to go to Copenhagen Central Station
because that's where I drove to get to
the Microsoft office
in Lyngby.
So, here you can see that you get
different options for the route that you
took. Um you might recognize this is
also similar to the web app, but um
we're getting the mobile application
also to do all of this powerful
recognizing and uh handling. So, I can
choose which of the routes I picked. In
my case, this one is the fastest one,
even though it's the longest one. So,
that's the one I took.
And then I can choose my vehicle type.
In my case, it was just a car.
And you can see that I have uh my
distance, in my case it's it's in miles,
and how much the per diem the sorry um
the rate is calculated based on that.
And that's as simple as that, and I can
create also my mileage expenses.
Now, of course, the agent will now
recognize the this expense, and it will
try to categorize my expenses
um into expense reports, and you can see
that in the meantime uh it tried to
figure out that this air pass um that uh
receipt that I just uploaded belongs to
this training February 26, and it
created some new
expense reports for the other
um expenses that uploaded.
Um
very importantly, I want to mention that
uh we have a feature which is also
offline mode. So, let's say that all of
these that I'm doing um I'm actually
doing it, for example, on a train with a
bad internet connection, or maybe I'm
doing it on a plane um while I'm flying,
so I am in offline mode.
Then, you can already do some parts of
this, so you can already add your
receipts to the app. Notice we don't
process them immediately, we process
them the moment your connection comes
back. So, there is no processing really
locally, uh but we just kind of keep
them ready for you, and the moment you
go back online, we're going to upload
them and process them, and Expense Agent
is going to take care of all the magic
that you just saw and loved.
The last thing I want to mention is
that, of course, our mobile app um also
supports the submission experience and
the approval experience um just the same
way as our web app does. So, for
example, here, if I jump into my um
expense report training, February, you
can see that I have my airline ticket
here, and then I have an additional
business class internal flight, and
maybe some um
additional hotel um expense.
And the moment I'm happy and I've added
all of them, I can just click submit,
and then submit my expenses to my
approver.
Uh in my case, since my company is a
small company, so I am also the approver
for my own expenses, so I can see here
that the expense report that I just sent
is actually sent to me uh as an
approver. So, you actually have also the
full approver experience in the mobile
app, where you can review the single
expenses, and in case they're flagged,
you can also check um what are the
compliance issues, and in case um also
override them. And you can see that here
I can just review and then finally
approve the expense report once I'm
ready.
So, what you just saw basically is that
from the mobile app, you have the same
powerful um agent experience and the
same powerful options that you have from
the web application, where you can use
Expense agent, you can do mileage um
expenses, and you can upload receipts
directly using your phone camera and
native capabilities. And all of that is
coming to you in the mobile app for
expense agent.
And now for my last slide, you might
ask, how do I get to try out the expense
agent mobile app? And the answer is you
can try it out right now.
But be mindful because it's still in
preview. So, there might still be some
functionalities that we need to like
figure out and fix a little bit. But you
can read our documentation scanning QR
code on the left, or you can download
directly the app for your iOS or Android
phone.
Please remember that the app is still in
beta, which means you will get to accept
some beta conditions and beta program
before you can actually download the
app. But you can do it just today as
long as you have an environment in
Business Central that supports the
expense agent.
Thank you for your attention.